MORE PEOPLE ARE NOW ELIGIBLE
UNDER PHASE 1B.
GOVERNOR JB PRITZKER
ANNOUNCED TODAY THAT PEOPLE WITH
COMORBIDITIES
WILL BE ELIGIBLE FOR A VACCINE
IN THIS CURRENT PHASE.
THIS IS SLATED TO BEGIN FEBRUARY
25TH.
AND THIS GUIDANCE COMES FROM THE
CDC.
BUT THOSE WHO ARE
UNDER 65 AND LIVE WITH
COMORBIDITIES HAVE A
RISK OF SERIOUS
COMPLICATIONS OR EVEN
DEATH IF THEY CONTRACT COVID-19.
HERE IS THAT LIST OF CONDITIONS
WHERE PATIENTS ARE ELIGIBLE FOR
THE VACCINE.
THEY ARE -- CANCER -- CHRONIC
KIDNEY DISEASE -- COPD --
DIABETES --
HEART CONDITIONS -- IMMUNOCOM
PROMISED STATE
FROM A SOLID ORGAN TRANSPLANT --
OBESITY --
PREGNANCY --
PULMONARY DISEASE -- SICKLE CELL
DISEASE
THIS EXPANSION OF PHASE 1B WILL
GREATLY INCREASE THE NEED FOR
VACCINES--
WHILE SUPPLY IS STILL LOW HERE
LOCALLY.
ACCORDING TO WINNEBAGO
COUNTY PUBLIC HEALTH
ADMINISTRATOR -- DR. SANDRA
MARTELL -- IT'S A CHALLENGE TO
PLACE AN EXACT NUMBER ON HOW
MANY PEOPLE ARE IN THIS
EXPANSION.
THAT'S BECAUSE SOMEONE MAY
QUALIFY FOR PHASE 1A BECAUSE OF
THEIR JOB -- AND QUALIFY FOR
PHASE 1B BECAUSE OF THEIR
COMORBIDITY.
MARTELL SAYS CURRENTLY --
ABOUT 60- THOUSAND PEOPLE
REGISTERED FOR A VACCINE WITH
THE HEALTH DEPARTMENT.
WELL I THINK WE'RE
CONCERNED IN PHASE 1B TO BEGIN
WITH THAT WE
DON'T HAVE ENOUGH.
WE DID LEARN TODAY THAT
WINNEBAGO COUNTY IS BEHIND ON
VACCINES BECAUSE IT DIDN'T
RECEIVE A SHIPMENT THIS WEEK.
COMING UP TONIGHT AT SIX -- WHAT
WE KNOW SO FAR ABOUT THIS AND
WHAT YOU CAN EXPECT IF YOUR
APPOINTMENT
WAS CANCELED.
ACCORDING TO THE HEALTH
DEPARTMENT -- THE MOST COMMON
COMORBIDITY IN WINNEBAGO COUNTY
-- IS OBSESITY.
AND NOW PEOPLE WHO ARE OBESE ARE
ELIGIBLE UNDER PHASE 1B -- WE
ASKED DR. MARTELL WHO OR WHAT
DEFINES OBESITY. AND SHE SAID
THAT -- AND EVERY OTHER
COMORBIDITY -- IS UP TO EACH
PATIENT TO REPORT.
YOU'RE PUTTING IN YOUR
OWN INFORMATION AND YOU'RE
ATTESTING TO IT. RIGHT? SO WE'RE
NOT
ASKING YOU TO PRODUCE PROOF THAT
YOU'RE
OBESE OR PROOF OF
WHERE YOU WORK OR
WHAT YOU DO.
OBVIOUSLY IN YOUR WORK SITE.
BUT IT'S AN HONOR SYSTEM, RIGHT?
AND THE SAME GOES FOR
PEOPLE WITH DISABILITIES -- WHO
ARE NOW ALSO ELIGIBLE FOR
VACCINES UNDER PHASE 1B.
WE'RE GOING TO ASK FOR
SOME MORE CLARIFICATION ABOUT
HOW DO WE ASK THAT QUESTION
ABOUT
DISABILITY BECAUSE THAT WAS NOT
ONE OF THE
COMORBIDITIES THE NATIONAL
ACADEMIES
HAD COME FORWARD WITH IN TERMS
OF VACCINATION PRIORITY FOR
COVID. SO WE'RE GOING TO ASK FOR
CLARIFICATION AND BUILD THOSE
QUESTIONS INTO THE REGISTRATION
SYSTEM.
AND FINALLY -- WE'RE WORKING
TO FIND OUT MORE ABOUT WHAT THIS
MEANS FOR PREGNANT PEOPLE -- NOW
ELIGIBLE UNDER PHASE 1B. WHAT
YOU NEED TO KNOW IF YOU ARE
PREGNANT -- OR BREASTFEEDING
BEFORE YOU GET VACCINATED --
COMING UP TONIGHT ON 13
NEWS AT SIX.
WE KNOW YOU HAVE
QUESTIONS ABOUT THE VACCINE AND
THE DIFFERENT PHASES OF THIS
ROLLOUT. YOU MIGHT HAVE
QUESTIONS ABOUT DISTRIBUTION --
OR EVEN ABOUT ITS EFFECTIVENESS
STILL.
THE 13 WREX VACCINE TEAM
IS HERE TO ANSWER THOSE
QUESTIONS.
IF YOU HAVE SOMETHING REGARDING
THE VACCINE THAT YOU NEED US TO
DIG DEEPER IN TO -- WE'LL DO
THAT TOO. YOU CAN EMAIL VACCI
NE@WREX.COM AND ONE OF US ON OUR
VACCINE TEAM WILL WORK TO GET
YOU THOSE ANSWE